hello everyone
i'm travis tigert from the u.s
anti-doping agency or usana
it's great to see you and thanks for
taking a moment to review this video
we we know it's been an unprecedented
year and the challenges for all of us
have been enormous we hope that you're
safe and healthy
and are able to train in the way that
you otherwise could
of course we're excited for 2021. in a
lot of ways it's a fresh start
for many of us and we're certainly
excited for the opportunity to serve you
once again in 2021
in fact our fresh start begins with our
game plan game plan 2024
which is our new strategic plan you'll
see the same athlete focus
on doing what's best for clean sport and
clean athletes
and fighting hard to protect your right
to a level playing field
i think you also see that we're focused
on innovation to ensure that you have
the best
in class when it comes to the technology
that collects your sample
so you'll see most of you if you haven't
already our new innovero
safe system our new collection kit
you're also going to see if you haven't
already
a new collection method called dried
blood spot it's an innovative and really
cool way to collect
blood for purposes of anti-doping
detection you simply put this on your
arm can be
self-administered in some circumstances
but our dcos will be bringing that out
in and out of competition testing much
wider
this year in 2021 and of course we're
going to continue to advocate for your
rights at the global level
and i know many of you that followed it
were disappointed as we were
with the outcome in the russia
state-sponsored doping case before the
court of arbitration for sport
and we were extremely disappointed that
they reduced
the consequence and really didn't put in
effect a very meaningful consequence
given the nature of the state-sponsored
doping scheme
the cover-up to it and then the cover-up
to the cover-up
which you know unfortunately is going to
allow many athletes from russia who
participated
who gain the advantage of these
performance-enhancing drugs
to walk away scot-free we're going to
continue to push for justice
and hope that the system can improve to
ensure justice
and that adequate testing for all
athletes both here in the u.s
as well as in places like russia is in
place before the 2021
tokyo olympic and paralympic games and
there is some good news
on the global enforcement standpoint
because congress passed the rachinkov
anti-doping fraud act
many of you supported it and you may
know that it provides criminal liability
to coaches
doctors sport officials who conspire to
dope athletes at major international
competitions so
if you have any information or evidence
about that please continue to bring that
forward
and we'll ensure that that act works
you're also
familiar with our play clean line we had
close to 500
tips to it last year and through our
robust internal legal and
investigative process we were able to
carry out or conduct
many targeted tests based off that
information and had roughly
a 22 positivity rate based on those
targeted tests based on the information
that you provided
so please continue to do that it helps
ensure that the playing field is level
and clean of course it's an honor even
in the challenging 2020 year
to support you and be here for for you
and we're looking really forward to 2021
to standing beside you to support your
right to clean sport and i promise you
we're going to do everything in our
power
to earn your trust and to demonstrate to
you not only in our words but in our
action
that we're going to fight hard for your
rights so that you can enjoy
the fruits of your sacrifice in doing it
the right way
so thank you